Edgar Quezada

Full-Stack Web Developer

+49 151 670 21847
edgar.quezada@gmail.com
Berlin, Germany
(open for remote work)

www.linkedin.com/in/edgarjquezada/

github.com/EJQuezada

Junior Full-Stack Web Developer with a background in legal and over 20 years of experience working with teams and stakeholders. Extensive experience with electronic discovery and electronic file management teams to improve and streamline digitization of documents. Able to efficiently translate creative ideas into stable and high-performing web applications through strong analytical and creative skills. Proficient with writing clear, concise, and effective web development code using current best practices.

WEB DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

Front End:

- Website building using HTML, CSS, JS, and Ruby
- Code linting & accessibility testing
- Libraries (Bootstrap)/Frameworks
- Responsive design, modals, and touch interactions
- Test & Behavior Driven Development: unit testing (Jest), integration testing (Cucumber), acceptance testing, and end-to-end testing(Puppeteer)
- Continuous integration/delivery
- Functional & Object oriented programming
- Mobile Applications using React Native, Expo, PWA

Back End:

- Node.js & Express
- APIs (JSON, RESTful, Postman)
- Hosting & Web Services (AWS, Google Firestore, Netlify, Heroku, GitHub Pages)
- Relational and non-relational databases (PostgreSQL, MongoDB)
- JWT Authentication and Authorization with Password middleware

Other Dev Tools:

- Git (Version control)
- Chrome Dev Tools
- Android Studio
- Trello, Slack, Zoom, Meet and Skype
- Sublime, Atom, and Visual Studio Code

EDUCATION

- Learn to Code with Ruby <u>Udemy.com</u> (01/2024 - 03/2024)
- Full-Stack Web Developer CareerFoundry, Berlin (10/2022 – 11/2023)
- **Juris Doctor** GGU School of Law, San Francisco (08/2010 -05/2013)

LANGUAGES

Native: English, SpanishC1 level: German, Italian

• A2 level: Catalan

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

myFlix, Web App, CareerFoundry study project — **05/2023 - 07/2023**

- Created a non-relational database (MongoDB) sampling movies from personal collection and user data. Database includes movie description, director information, classification, and release date;
- Built a REST API with Node.js and Express using Mongoose to allow users to interact with the database;
- Tested API endpoints using Postman, while also writing clean and concise documentation for the app, and ultimately deploying the application via Netlify.

ChatApp, PWA, CareerFoundry study project — **07/2023 - 09/2023**

- Developed a progressive web application (responsive, cross-platform, offline available) using React to display a list/chart of events from Google calendar;
- Followed test-driven-development approach, translating user-stories into scenarios for unit and integration testing (Jest), acceptance testing (Cucumber), and end-to-end testing (Puppeteer).

WORK EXPERIENCE

Legal Advisor, ReviverMX, San Francisco, CA— **06/2013 - 06/2020**

- Drafted, prepared, and filed corporate filings for tech-startup company with multiple stakeholders requiring daily updates;
- Advised founders about corporate structuring to improve internal operations and limit shareholder liability;
- Managed and negotiated early resolution of legal disputes with former personnel and vendors in different time zones resulting in favorable and expedient resolution.

Associate Attorney, Hanna Brophy, Oakland, CA — **06/2015 - 09/2018**

- Managed 150+ disputed claim files simultaneously requiring almost daily communications with clients and opposing counsel for expedient resolution of claims;
- Trained claim adjusters to provide best resolution of legal claims to mitigate liability and/or settle cases before trial stage.

Law Clerk, Offices of M. Randle, San Francisco, CA — **06/2013 - 05/2015**

- Developed an electronic file management system for solo-practitioner with 50+ cases to track communications, legal filing deadlines, and court filing deadlines for each active case;
- Analyzed legal files to prepare litigation calendar, determine legal claims and defenses, and draft legal pleadings/discovery.